<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.9.2">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2023-02-07T19:01:35-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Isaac Fleck</title><subtitle>Isaac Fleck - A Technical Product Owner with 6+ years of experience in software development, leading teams,  and driving product development.</subtitle><author><name>Isaac Fleck</name></author><entry><title type="html">Stack Sheriff</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/projects/stack-sheriff/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Stack Sheriff" /><published>2023-01-18T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2023-02-03T16:22:02-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/projects/stack-sheriff</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/projects/stack-sheriff/">&lt;h1 id=&quot;stack-sheriff---stack-exchange-article-management-tool&quot;&gt;Stack Sheriff - Stack Exchange Article Management tool&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;project-summary&quot;&gt;Project Summary&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Create a tool where we could track and validate if a stack exchange article was still relevant. this would be used to create training materials for the business and our Tier 1 support group decreasing the number of escalations our Engineers had to handle during their on call shift.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;project-timeline&quot;&gt;Project Timeline&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;None - Extra task that I took on to improve the life of engineers within the department&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;project-description&quot;&gt;Project Description&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some key points of the projects:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Developed an application written in Python to Assist in the management Internal StackExchange (SE) articles&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Data Gathered through SE’s API on timed intervals&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Written in an Object Oriented structure to allow other teams to implement the solution&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Managed Articles utilizing Tags to allow for easy searching and management by the owning developing team&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;skills-and-technologys&quot;&gt;Skills and technology’s&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Python&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;StackExchange API Integration&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content><author><name>Isaac Fleck</name></author><category term="Projects" /><category term="Business Analyst" /><category term="Automation" /><category term="Software Development" /><category term="Internal Project" /><summary type="html">Stack Sheriff - Stack Exchange Article Management tool Project Summary Create a tool where we could track and validate if a stack exchange article was still relevant. this would be used to create training materials for the business and our Tier 1 support group decreasing the number of escalations our Engineers had to handle during their on call shift.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">OnCall Volume Reduction</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/projects/oncall-reduction/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="OnCall Volume Reduction" /><published>2023-01-07T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2023-02-03T16:22:02-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/projects/oncall-reduction</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/projects/oncall-reduction/">&lt;h1 id=&quot;oncall-volume-reduction&quot;&gt;OnCall Volume Reduction&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;project-summary&quot;&gt;Project Summary&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Perform an analysis on the on call volume that impacted our engineers to identify areas we can improve to reduce the work performed over an iteration.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;project-timeline&quot;&gt;Project Timeline&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2-4 weeks&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;project-description&quot;&gt;Project Description&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some tasks that I performed over the life of the project included:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Reviewed and provided metrics on initial and final state post initiative&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Worked with Application Databases and API’s to aggregate data related to On-Call Tickets&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Identified and ranked error messages based on impact and potential resolutions&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Presented data to senior developers for approval&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Created agile artifacts (Epic, Features, and Stories) for development teams to work&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Reported on final reduction of 35% ticket reduction equating to a reduction of ~140 man hours monthly&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;skills-and-technologys&quot;&gt;Skills and technology’s&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Python&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;SQL&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content><author><name>Isaac Fleck</name></author><category term="Projects" /><category term="Business Analyst" /><category term="Software Development" /><category term="Client Facing" /><category term="Internal Project" /><summary type="html">OnCall Volume Reduction Project Summary Perform an analysis on the on call volume that impacted our engineers to identify areas we can improve to reduce the work performed over an iteration.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Propel</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/projects/propel/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Propel" /><published>2022-12-01T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2023-02-03T16:22:02-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/projects/propel</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/projects/propel/">&lt;h1 id=&quot;propel-an-enterprise-automation-tool&quot;&gt;Propel: An Enterprise Automation Tool&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;project-summary&quot;&gt;Project Summary&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The goal of Propel was to create a tool that would automate the process of creating all of the infrastructure required for a developer to create a new application.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;project-timeline&quot;&gt;Project Timeline&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;None Defined - Project took 6 Months from initial artifact creation to hand off of the MVP to the enterprise engineering team&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;project-description&quot;&gt;Project Description&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our target for this application was to reduce the previous 3-5 day process that involved an engineer standing up all of the required resources for a new applications. These resources included:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;GitHub Repo&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;CircleCI Pipelines&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Terraform YAML Files&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Application Information Records&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We wanted this tool to be adapted by the organization as a whole, so we focused on creating a framework where templates could be easily designed and managed by each system team. This would allow each department across the family of company’s to define and manage their own best practices suited to their workflows and requirements. Some common tasks that I performed over the life of the project included:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Creating timelines and negotiated expectations of deliveries in deliverable in usable intervals&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Delegated coding and testing of deliverables to the team during sprints&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Updated developers on deliverables through emails, demonstrations, and user acceptance testing&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Delivered metrics before, after, and at each phase of the integration as applicable&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;skills-and-technologys&quot;&gt;Skills and technology’s&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Project Management&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Agile Artifact Creation&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Time Management&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Risk Management and Mitigation&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Python (Data Aggregation)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content><author><name>Isaac Fleck</name></author><category term="Projects" /><category term="Product Owner" /><category term="Internal Project" /><summary type="html">Propel: An Enterprise Automation Tool Project Summary The goal of Propel was to create a tool that would automate the process of creating all of the infrastructure required for a developer to create a new application.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">New Escrow Experience</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/projects/new-escrow-experience/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="New Escrow Experience" /><published>2022-06-30T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2023-02-03T16:22:02-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/projects/new-escrow-experience</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/projects/new-escrow-experience/">&lt;h1 id=&quot;new-escrow-experience-in-rms&quot;&gt;New Escrow Experience in RMS&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;project-summary&quot;&gt;Project Summary&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Revamp the Rocket Mortgage Escrow Experience for clients who have an Escrow account. The goal was to provide a better experience and more visibility into escrow accounts with hopes of reducing calls to our client relations team.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;project-timeline&quot;&gt;Project Timeline&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Q2 through Q4 where MVP was delivered by Start of Q3&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;project-description&quot;&gt;Project Description&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some common tasks that I performed over the life of the project included:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Defining integration, requirements/acceptance criteria, and mapping of fields&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Created timelines and negotiated expectations of deliveries in deliverable and usable intervals&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Delegated coding and testing of deliverables to the team during iteration sprints&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Updated business clients on deliverables through emails, demonstrations, and user acceptance testing&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Delivered metrics before, after, and at each phase of the integration&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Ensured all UI/UX branding and standards of Rocket Mortgage were incorporated in client-facing design and usability&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Performed and coordinated User Acceptance Testing for each deliverable of the new experience&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;skills-and-technologys&quot;&gt;Skills and technology’s&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Project Management&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Agile Artifact Creation&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Time Management&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Risk Management and Mitigation&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Python (Data Aggregation)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;User Acceptance Testing&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content><author><name>Isaac Fleck</name></author><category term="Projects" /><category term="Product Owner" /><category term="Client Facing" /><summary type="html">New Escrow Experience in RMS Project Summary Revamp the Rocket Mortgage Escrow Experience for clients who have an Escrow account. The goal was to provide a better experience and more visibility into escrow accounts with hopes of reducing calls to our client relations team.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Uptime Report Automation</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/projects/uptime-report-automation/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Uptime Report Automation" /><published>2022-01-01T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2022-01-01T16:22:02-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/projects/uptime-report-automation</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/projects/uptime-report-automation/">&lt;h1 id=&quot;uptime-report-automation&quot;&gt;Uptime Report Automation&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;project-summary&quot;&gt;Project Summary&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The goal of this project was to automate the data aggregation, presentation and sending of a monthly report detailing front end availability for the prior month.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When the assignment was originally handed off, the data sources for the three front ends lived in separate places and often relied on Subject Matter Experts to compile and report the required metrics. This process was lengthy and typically required meetings increasing the effort needed to deliver the report.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All said and done, the report creation processes was reduced from 3-4 days, involving meetings with four different senior engineers (~30 minutes to 2 hours) a month; to ~2-3 hours only impacting my day.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;table&gt;
  &lt;thead&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;th&gt;Role&lt;/th&gt;
      &lt;th&gt;Old Cost&lt;/th&gt;
      &lt;th&gt;New Cost&lt;/th&gt;
      &lt;th&gt;Reduction&lt;/th&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;/thead&gt;
  &lt;tbody&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Product Owner&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;$1,907.84&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;$178&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;90.67% (-$1,729.84)&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Senior Engineer&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;$641.52&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;$0&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;100% (-641.52)&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Monthly Total&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;$2,849.36&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;$178&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;93.75% (-$2,671.36)&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Yearly Total&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;$34,192.32&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;$2,136&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;93.75% (-$32,056.32)&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;please note the above salary’s were calculated using company averages per Glassdoor&lt;/em&gt;
  &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.glassdoor.com/Salary/Rocket-Companies-Product-Owner-Salaries-E7856_D_KO17,30.htm&quot;&gt;$124,000 PerYear&lt;/a&gt; = $59.62 an Hour &lt;br /&gt;
  &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.glassdoor.com/Salary/Rocket-Companies-Senior-Software-Engineer-Salaries-E7856_D_KO17,41.htm&quot;&gt;$166,800 PerYear&lt;/a&gt; = $80.19 an Hour&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;project-timeline&quot;&gt;Project Timeline&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;45 Days from start to sending out the first report using the new automated process&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;project-description&quot;&gt;Project Description&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Utilizing Python to gather data from PagerDuty, Grafana and Dynatrace’s API’s. I was able to automate the collection and presentation of the Technical Incidents that effected specific Business Services in Pagerduty. To track individual user impact, I connected to different Grafana dashboards and Dynatrace data sources to track the 500 responses.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once the data was collected, I performed a simple calculation reducing the total uptime for the three target front ends based on the time an Incident spent in a Severity 1 or 2 state, while highlighting the number of 500 responses outside of recorded incident time frames.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;From here, the python script automatically created a .docx file containing a bar chart visualizing the downtime, and a section for each front end that detailed the incidents that impacted said front end.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;From here I verified the data, constructed an email communication that highlighted the important details. then sent the file as a PDF to leaders across the Organization&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;skills-and-technologys&quot;&gt;Skills and technology’s&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Python&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Data Visualization&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Enterprise Wide Communications&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content><author><name>Isaac Fleck</name></author><category term="Projects" /><category term="Business Analyst" /><category term="Automation" /><category term="Software Development" /><category term="Site Reliability Engineering" /><category term="Internal Project" /><summary type="html">Uptime Report Automation Project Summary The goal of this project was to automate the data aggregation, presentation and sending of a monthly report detailing front end availability for the prior month.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">AWS Migrations</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/projects/aws-migrations/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="AWS Migrations" /><published>2021-12-31T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2023-02-03T16:22:02-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/projects/aws-migrations</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/projects/aws-migrations/">&lt;h1 id=&quot;aws-account-migrations&quot;&gt;AWS Account Migrations&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;project-summary&quot;&gt;Project Summary&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our target was to move the AWS resources for each Release Train from a centralized AWS Account to their own account. This would allow the SRE Team to better manage AWS resources and track spending more efficiently.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;project-timeline&quot;&gt;Project Timeline&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2-3 Months&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;project-description&quot;&gt;Project Description&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Worked with each team and their architect to identify requirements/acceptance criteria and optimal migration timing&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Created Agile artifacts for the SRE Team to work through and deliver on during weekly sprints&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Performed UAT Testing to ensure functionality remained after migration&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Delivered Technology wide communications regarding migrations&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Performed triage duties in the event of an incident&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;skills-and-technologys&quot;&gt;Skills and technology’s&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Project Management&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Agile Artifact Creation&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Time Management&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Risk Management and Mitigation&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Python (Data Aggregation)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content><author><name>Isaac Fleck</name></author><category term="Projects" /><category term="Product Owner" /><category term="Site Reliability Engineering" /><category term="Internal Project" /><summary type="html">AWS Account Migrations Project Summary Our target was to move the AWS resources for each Release Train from a centralized AWS Account to their own account. This would allow the SRE Team to better manage AWS resources and track spending more efficiently.</summary></entry></feed>